Guide to Central Washington University, Arlen James "Jim" Hawkins Faculty Papers encodinganalog="date" normal= "1970/2002">1970-2002
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
Central Washington University Faculty papers, Arlen Hawkins
1970-2002
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections 400 E University Way Ellensburg, WA 98926 (509) 963-1717 http://www.lib.cwu.edu/Archives-Special-Collections archives@cwu.edu
FP-0045
Hawkins, Arlen
14.18 linear feet. This collection includes 19 puppets, and 21 laminated illustrations of stage and character design by Arlen James Hawkins. 5 textile boxes, 2 over-size boxes
A collection of puppets and drawings made by Arlen "Jim" Hawkins.
Brief Biography of Arlin James (Jim) Hawkins
Arlin James (Jim) Hawkins was a professor in the theatre arts department at Central Washington University from 1970-2002. During his tenure at CWU, he founded the Children's Theatre Touring program and the Youth Drama Major. Hawkins received many accolades for his work as a theatrical designer and puppeteer. He established the A. James Hawkins Children's Theatre Endowment in 2005. Hawkins was born May 14, 1938 in Minneapolis, Minnesota and passed away on July 23, 2013 in Yakima, Washington.
This collection spans the years 1970-2002, though Hawkins’ illustrations concentrate on the 1980s and 1990s. The second series contains illustrations created by Hawkins in the planning of upcoming theatrical productions at Central Washington University. Illustrations are in both black and white and color and some contain fabric samples for the costumes. The illustrations span 1984-1999.
The collection is organized into two series. The first series titled puppets contains 5 textile boxes holding 19 puppets. The second Series is titled: Theater illustrations, it contains two oversize flat boxes.
Open Acess for research>
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Hawkins, Jim
Colleges and Universities; Education
Fine Arts, Performing Arts, Artifacts
Professor
See Folder List Below
- Wizard (Box-folder 1-1)
- Elf (Box-folder 1-2)
- Old man (Box-folder 1-3)
- Boy (Box-folder 2-1)
- Lady (Box-folder 2-2)
- Small doll, Blue dress (Box-folder 2-3)
- Misty Blue (Box-folder 2-4)
- Red hood, Grandmother (Box-folder 2-5)
- Older Female, Blonde (Box-folder 2-6)
- Plain puppet (Box-folder 3-1)
- Bucket (Box-folder 3-2)
- Puppet head (Box-folder 3-3)
- Boy (Box-folder 3-4)
- Blonde Male (Box-folder 3-5)
- Tom-Kitten (Box-folder 4-1)
- Fox (Box-folder 4-2)
- Man in Dresscoat (Box-folder 4-3)
- Wild-man (Box-folder 5-1)
- Punch (Box-folder 5-2)
- Romeo (Box-folder 5-3)
- Absence and Old Lace (Box-folder 6-1)
- Amadeus (Box-folder 6-2)
- Beauty and the Beast, 1999 (Box-folder 6-3)
- Braggart Soldier, 1984 (Box-folder 6-4)
- Bullshot Crummond (Box-folder 6-5)
- Candide (Box-folder 6-6)
- Charlotte's Web, 1991 (Box-folder 6-7)
- Chips (Box-folder 6-8)
- Die Fledermaus (Box-folder 6-9)
- Hansel and Gretel (Box-folder 6-10)
- Isn't It Romantic, 1986 (Box-folder 6-11)
- Knock Knock, 1986 (Box-folder 6-12)
- Macbeth, 1986 (Box-folder 6-13)
- Miracle Worker (Box-folder 6-14)
- Miser, 1986 (Box-folder 7-1)
- My Fair Lady (Box-folder 7-2)
- Red Shoes, 1985 (Box-folder 7-3)
- Romeo and Juliet (Box-folder 7-4)
- Royal Hunt of the Sun (Box-folder 7-5)
- Rumba Tiya (Box-folder 7-6)
- Toby Show (Box-folder 7-7)
- Visit, 1988 (Box-folder 7-8)
- Wiley and the Hairy man (Box-folder 7-9)